exploroo.com 2015-12-06

# Privacy Policy - Exploroo

This Privacy Policy was last updated on the following date: 6th April 2009

If you have any queries in relation to this Privacy Policy, you can email us at: support@exploroo.com This is a legal document which sets out how Exploroo handles data which identifies you. This Privacy Policy forms part of our Term and Conditions. At Exploroo we believe strongly in protecting the privacy of our Members’ personal information. This statement describes the privacy practices we apply for the EXPLOROO Service. As part of that, it also expresses our approach to complying with the data protection laws which apply in Australia If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should contact the Exploroo customer services at dataprotection[@EXPLOROO.com](http://exploroo.com/members/exploroo.com/).

1\. The information we gather and track

Information gathered on registration. When you register for the EXPLOROO Service, you provide your name, your email address, your gender, your date of birth, nationality, your location details and some optional details about yourself. They are available to you, and capable of being corrected or updated, through your EXPLOROO profile page

Cookies. We use small files known as “cookies” to enhance users’ experience of the Exploroo Service as follows:

* To hold Members’ login information, so that your location details and contact information are displayed when you visit the EXPLOROO Service. This option can be disabled by clicking the “logoff” icon which appears at the top right hand corner of every page.  
* To facilitate optimal use of the EXPLOROO Service by Members, by means of a temporary “session” cookie. These cookies disappear when the Member’s browser session ends, or if the Member clicks the “logoff” icon which appears on the EXPLOROO Service.  
* In the course of running advertisements or sponsored areas on this site, a third-party advertiser or sponsor may place on your browser (and subsequently recognize) a unique cookie or pixel.  
* The EXPLOROO Service also includes cookies provided by an online advertising network that helps more precisely to target advertising to Members, based on their activity on this and other sites within the network.  
* The cookies on the EXPLOROO Service do not access or use information by which people can be personally identified. If you wish, you can prevent these files from using non-personal information about you by either deleting the cookie folder in your browser or by putting your browser’s Privacy setting higher, but doing so will mean that you will not be able to use the EXPLOROO Service in the way that we intend it to be used, will not be presented with advertising that reflects the way that you use our, and other, websites and may well adversely affect your experience of websites that use cookies to enhance or personalize that experience.  
* You can find out how to make these changes to your browser at this site: http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/

2\. Access to Personally Identifiable Information

The information we collect may be used:

* To process your payment for membership subscriptions or other goods or services ordered on our site or to fulfill such orders.  
* To provide our customer support service and to verify any claims or requests you make if you use our customer support service.  
* To enforce our terms and conditions and prevent or detect hacking activities, security breaches or safety risks in connection with our websites.  
* To send service announcements and messages. For example, a reminder is sent to members if a subscription payment is due.  
* To aggregate information to generate anonymous statistics regarding use of our websites. We may share this anonymous information with our partners and advertisers. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person.  
* For our own internal marketing and demographic studies and to help us improve our website.  
* In the event of an actual or proposed (including as part of negotiations for any) merger, or business combination or sale of substantially all of our assets or a business operation to which such information relates or as provided under bankruptcy or applicable insolvency laws or by the enforcement of equitable rights.

If your personally identifiable information or email address changes, or if you no longer wish to be a Member of the EXPLOROO Service, you may correct, update, delete or deactivate your Membership through the Member’s account settings menu option found at the top of most pages when logged on to the EXPLOROO Service. Alternatively, you can email EXPLOROO Customer Support at the following email: support@exploroo.com. We will endeavour to respond to all email enquires within 2 working days.

3\. Emails you receive from EXPLOROO

As part of the EXPLOROO Service, EXPLOROO sends Members these newsletters and emails. You may also receive email notifications when you have new mail in your EXPLOROO inbox or when you have received a reply to your “Chatboard” topic.

4\. Choice / Opt-Out

We provide you the opportunity to ‘opt-out’ of having your personally identifiable information used for certain purposes during the registration process and from the “privacy preferences” option within the site, accessible from the Member’s account settings menu option, found at the top of most web pages when logged on to the EXPLOROO Service.

You may opt out of any or all of the newsletters and emails we send you (see paragraph 3 above) by changing your Interaction Options at any time. Your “Interaction Options” can be accessed from the Member’s account settings menu option found at the top of most web pages when logged on to the EXPLOROO Service.

You may also opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or email we send you or by emailing us at: support@exploroo.com with your request.

5\. Sharing and use of information

Any visitor to the EXPLOROO Service anywhere in the world can view your profile information and photos that you have uploaded to the EXPLOROO.com community. You can control what part of your profile information and photos is visible to visitors of the EXPLOROO.com website and which network of EXPLOROO.com members can see what information.

The over-riding principles we apply are these:

We, and (where relevant) our credit card processing agents, will not supply your personal data to a third party for commercial exploitation except as consented to by you in accordance with prevailing law.

Profile Information. Once a Member selects a location, some or all of the information held for that Member, except for the email address, telephone numbers and passwords, will be publicly available at the listing for that location.

Your home location, in terms of your town / city, state / county and country, and any other location specific information you submit to the EXPLOROO Service must be considered at all times to be publicly available information, save where you specify (in the Privacy options that apply to your profile) that you wish your profile only to be viewable by either Members or friends. In addition, if address details are submitted to the EXPLOROO.com service they are not made publicly available.

Email addresses. We do not directly make your email address available to anyone on any screen of the EXPLOROO Service. Similarly, when you send an email to another Member through the EXPLOROO Service, neither the sender’s nor the recipient’s email address is disclosed by the EXPLOROO Service itself. Members can, however, choose to make their email addresses known to other Members; however, EXPLOROO does not recommend that you do so, and any such disclosure is at the Member’s own risk. Members may change the email address we hold them at any time by visiting “Edit Personal Details”, which is accessible from the Member’s account settings found at the top of most pages when logged on to the EXPLOROO Service. If your email system automatically responds to a contact email with a read or delivery receipt, your email address will be revealed. No tracking technologies are used within / in conjunction with emails nor do we share, sell, rent or trade PII with third parties for their promotional purposes.

Un-validated Memberships. If you register for the EXPLOROO Service, and you receive a validation email, but fail to validate your Membership then we may contact you via email at periods of 24 hours, 7 days, and 30 days at your registered email address to notify you of the invalid status. Should you fail to respond to these notifications then we may send you one final notice before the un-validated Membership is removed.

Advertising. The EXPLOROO Service may include interactive advertising for other businesses. We may use, and provide to third parties, anonymous demographic data provided by Members to target this advertising more appropriately.

Telephone numbers. You may enter a contact telephone number in your Personal Details. This number is for internal use only, for future or current services such as SMS. Your number will never be disclosed to any third party without your prior consent. Should we introduce an additional service which utilises telephone numbers, or we wish to provide you with informational content via your mobile phone, you will be given the option to agree to this, as we believe it should be your choice what services you receive.

Notification of unread messages. If you have a number of messages waiting for you in your EXPLOROO mailbox, and you have not logged in to the service for an extended period, we may at our discretion contact you via your registered email address to notify you of the unread messages. Should you still not read and remove these messages then we may remove the messages as part of our data cleansing process.

Credit Card information. There has been a lot of publicity about Credit Card security on the Internet so we work with the leading Merchant Providers in the industry who specialize in Fraud and Data Verification. These companies include Paypal. Members’ credit or debit card information is encrypted and stored securely. We share your billing information with such companies insofar as necessary for the processing of your payment or to prevent or detect fraud. These companies have agreed not to retain, share, store or use your personally identifiable information for any secondary purpose.

EXPLOROO companies and subsidiaries. We may share data supplied by you (or collected about you) with our subsidiaries and other companies owned by us, but only for the purposes described in this policy.

Changes in EXPLOROO’s business. If all of the assets which EXPLOROO uses to operate its business (or substantially all of them) are acquired by a third party, we may transfer personal data we then hold to that party.

Place of processing. The computers and companies that process data on our behalf are based in the Australia and other countries. Thus, your personal data (which may include data revealing racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, or trade union membership, or concerning health or sex life) may be transferred to, processed and held both inside and outside Australia. Countries outside Australia may not have as well developed data protection laws in place to protect your information as those inside Australia, but we will ensure your personal data is treated in compliance with those laws and this Privacy Policy.

6\. Sharing Information

When you use the EXPLOROO Service, you may form relationships, send messages, perform searches and queries, form groups, set up events, and transmit information through various channels. We collect this information so that we can provide you the service and offer personalized features. In most cases, we retain it so that, for instance, you can return to view prior messages you have sent or easily see your friend list. [When you update information, we usually keep a backup copy of the prior version for a reasonable period of time to enable reversion to the prior version of that information. You post a User Submission (as defined in the EXPLOROO Terms and Conditions) on the EXPLOROO Service at your own risk. Although we allow you to set privacy options that limit access to your pages, please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. We cannot control the actions of other Users with whom you may choose to share your pages and information. Therefore, we cannot and do not guarantee that User Submissions you post on the Site will not be viewed by unauthorized persons. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the Site. You understand and acknowledge that, even after removal, copies of User Submissions may remain viewable in cached and archived pages or if other Users have copied or stored your User Submissions.

Exploroo Ltd may also collect information about you from other sources, such as newspapers, blogs, instant messaging services, and other users of the EXPLOROO.com service through the operation of the service (e.g. photo tags) in order to provide you with more useful information and a more personalized experience.

When you register for the EXPLOROO Service, you can create your own profile and determine your own privacy settings.

Your name and profile picture thumbnail will be available in all search results across the EXPLOROO.com network and may be searchable through third party web-sites with which we partner (such as sites for which we provide a social network service) and third party search engines, and may be automatically notified to third party tracking websites/weblogs; in each case, you can prevent this happening by specifying (in the Privacy options that apply to your profile) that you wish your profile only to be viewable by either Members or friends.

The fact that your EXPLOROO profile has been added or updated, as well as a short extract from the title page of your EXPLOROO profile, may be automatically notified to third party tracking websites/weblogs (thus increasing the traffic to the EXPLOROO Service, and potentially to your own EXPLOROO profile). This can also be prevented by specifying (in the Privacy options) that you wish your profile only to be viewable by either Members or friends. If you do so, this will prevent subsequent notifications to third party tracking websites/weblogs, but notifications prior to the time when you make the change to your profile’s Privacy options may continue to appear on those websites/weblogs.

Your news feeds and friends feeds may aggregate the information you provide and make it available to your friends and network members according to your privacy settings. You may set your preferences for your news feeds at any time by adjusting your Privacy Settings.

7\. Security

We have security measures in place to protect our customer database and access to this database is restricted internally. However, it remains each Member’s responsibility:

* to protect against unauthorised access to Your Details;  
* to ensure against use by anyone else of the EXPLOROO Service through the machine that Member uses while they are “logged on” to the EXPLOROO Service;  
* to log off or exit from the EXPLOROO Service when not using it;  
* and to keep his/her password secret.  
* our Security team can be reached via dataprotection[@EXPLOROO.com](http://exploroo.com/members/exploroo.com/)  
* EXPLOROO.com strives to protect the Personal Information and email address you provide through our site, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure

8\. Remove details

You may have your registration details removed at any time. To remove yourself, please in your profile click the radio button “switch off profile”.

9\. Invite a Friend

If Members elect to permit EXPLOROO to search email addresses held within their email service on their behalf and click on “Import & Invite Friends”, they accept that by doing so, an email invitation will be sent on their behalf, to the relevant email address, and that a reminder email could be sent to that contact on their behalf. In addition, if Members click on “Refer a Friend” or opt to Invite a Friend from any other link on the EXPLOROO website, and submit email addresses of their contacts to invite to join the EXPLOROO Service, they accept that by doing so, an email invitation will be sent on their behalf, to the relevant email address, and that a reminder email could be sent to that contact on their behalf. By inviting their contacts to join the site, the Member agrees that they have obtained prior consent from their contacts (a) to send them such an invitation and a reminder, and (b) to allow the other action referred to in this Clause and in Clause 8. EXPLOROO stores the name and email address of the contacts for the purpose of automatically adding the respondent to the contacts list of the Member sending the invitation and to send a reminder to that invitation on the Member’s behalf. The Members’ username and password will not be saved anywhere on the site. EXPLOROO does not sell these email addresses or use them to send any other communication besides invitations and the reminder to an invitation on behalf of the Member. The Member or the Contact of the Member’s contacts can request the removal of their details from our database at any time by sending an email to: remove[@EXPLOROO.com](http://exploroo.com/members/exploroo.com/).

10\. Importing your Contacts

If Members elect to import their contacts, they accept that by doing so, an email invitation will be sent on their behalf, to the email addresses of the contacts that are being imported and that a reminder email could be sent to that contact, on their behalf. By inviting their contacts to join the site, the Member agrees that they have obtained prior consent from their contacts to send them an invitation or a reminder to that invitation. EXPLOROO stores the name and email address of the contacts to enable the Member to contact their contacts via the EXPLOROO Service and to send them a reminder of that invitation on the Member’s behalf. The Member’s username and password will not be saved anywhere on the site. EXPLOROO does not sell these email addresses or use them to send any other communication besides invitations and the reminder of that invitation on behalf of the Member. The Member or the Member’s contacts can request the removal of their details from the EXPLOROO database at any time by sending an email to: remove[@EXPLOROO.com](http://exploroo.com/members/exploroo.com/).

11\. Disclosure for legal reasons

We reserve the right to communicate such of a Member’s personal information as we hold to third parties which seek the disclosure of it, and which make a legally-compliant request for its disclosure.

Legal Disclaimer  
We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site

12\. Contacting Exploroo

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with Exploroo, you can contact us at support@exploroo.com . You can also use this address if you wish to request from a copy of the personal data we hold about you or a description of that data from Exploroo. Please note that by English law we are entitled to charge you a small sum for providing this information.

13\. Links to third party sites

Our site contains links to other sites. Exploroo is not responsible for the privacy practices, or the content, of those web sites or services of other companies or organizations to which we link or which link to us or which provide goods or services to our users from their web sites (such as co-branded, white label or affiliate sites)

14\. Changes to this Privacy Policy

If we decide to change our Privacy Policy or email practices, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page.
